This video will explain how to use the LiveSync plugin to easily realize the connection between Claw and UE.
First, download UE.
Search for Epic.
Go to the Epic official website.
Click to log in.
If you don't have an Epic account, you need to use an email to register.
If you have an account, just click to log in.
After logging in, click the upper left corner.
Find the virtual machine, then click to get the virtual machine.
We can directly click to download the program.
If you have any questions about the installation method,
you can also click to view the installation method.
This is the official recording of the UE installation method tutorial.
We can now click to download the installation program.
Below is the installation UE configuration requirement.
Here is the installation graphics card and processor requirement of the Windows system.
This is the requirement of the Mac computer.
You can check to see if your computer's configuration can meet the requirements of the installation UE.
After downloading the program,
go to the download folder.
Find the Epic Games program.
Double-click to open it.
There will be a pop-up window like this.
You can install the program on a non-C drive.
This way, we can save the space of the C drive.
Go to a folder and click to confirm.
At this time,
the Epic Games program will appear on your desktop.
After the installation is completed,
the program window will appear.
Log in to the Epic account.
This account is the same as the Epic Games account that is registered on the Epic official website.
Their accounts are all the same.
After the login is completed,
you can see such a interface.
Here is the account information.
Then enter the virtual engine.
Find the version of the engine added here.
Click to add.
Or just click to install the engine.
Click to install.
Since the installation method of LiveSync after UE 5.6 is different,
it will explain the two installation methods.
Let's look at the first case.
Use UE 5.6.1 as an example.
Here,
you need to set the installation location of the engine.
I also choose to install it on a disk.
Save the space of the C disk.
Note that there is no Chinese or special characters in the engine installation path.
You can use English or Pinyin subtitles.
Click to install.
Installing takes some time.
We can install multiple versions of UE.
If you continue to click to add,
you can install different versions of UE.
This is the installation progress.
If we want to pause,
click this button.
You can also click to cancel the installation directly.
Here you can see the download progress.
This is the download progress.
Here is the location of all the engineering documents.
FAB Library.
This is the 3D assets added in FAB.
These are some of the 3D assets I added before.
If you are installing for the first time,
these three fields are blank.
Next, download Clou's LiveSync plugin.
Enter Connect Business.
Then find the application.
Find LiveSync.
Then click to download.
Select LiveSync to download the corresponding version.
Start from 2.0.1 LiveSync.
It will jump to FAB Business.
You can directly add it to my library here.
After entering my library,
you can click to check in the launcher.
Open and refresh.
You can see the LiveSync plugin of Clou MD.
Click to install the engine.
You can see that it is now prompting us.
The slot for adding the plugin is 5.6.
Click to install.
It takes some time to install.
It is now installed in the 5.6 engine.
Next, we will install another plugin.
Enter FAB and click to search for Substance.
Then find this plugin.
It is next to my library here.
Click to search.
Next, it sits in my library.
Follow the Goal with asterisk,
it will dish。
Yes, it's finally installed.
The fully installed plugin.
Next, with the remaining거를.
By clicking to show it to Clou,
Then select 5.6
You can see the engine version supported by it
Then click Install
I just demonstrated how to install LiveSync in the UE5.6 version
Then I will introduce to you
How to install LiveSync before UE5.6
First, let's add another engine version
We can add a 5.5
Then click Install
Also to modify the installation path
Click Install
After installation is complete
Then we also
Follow the same method
First, go to Install Substance
If the first installation is 5.5
Follow the same steps
Search Substance 3D for Unreal Engine in FAB
Add it to the library
It will appear in our FAB Library
Next, we follow the same method
Click Install to Engine
Now it is using 5.5 to add the plugin
Then click Install
Now our Substance plugin
Has been installed in the UE engine of 5.5
Next
Let's download LiveSync plugin 5.5
Open the LiveSync interface
You can see the plugin version corresponding to 5.5
The LiveSync version it downloaded is 2.0.0
Then it can also correspond to
Our 20.25.0.1.28 CLO version
Click it directly
It will download a compression package for us
After the compression package is downloaded
We directly click to open
解壓文件
After the compression is completed
Go back to this interface
Then enter this guide
This is how to set up the Unreal Engine
And LiveSync plugin instructions
After the compression is completed
We need to add this file
Put it in this UE directory
What you need to pay attention to is
If we install the UE path
Is outside the C drive
For example
I am installed in a drive
We need to find this path in a drive
Now let's find the path
This is the path where I installed UE 5.5
Double click to enter
Find the engine
Then find the plug-in
Then find the mark place
What you need to pay attention to here is
This file holder
Is needed after we have installed a certain plug-in
It will be here to create a file holder
Then you can see
Here it has a substance file holder
Then this is what we just installed
Substance plug-in
If we haven't installed a plug-in in advance
Then this file holder will not be created
Now we have to install the plugin
Now we find this file holder
That we have just decompressed
Copy
Paste
Now we will paste this plug-in
Next
We need to set these plugs in UE
Open the driver
Then click start
This is the UE window of the new project
Next, create a project
First, we need to set the location of the project
I set it in a disk
The project name needs to be in English
Don't use a special character
Simply type the name of the project
Then click create
Now this initial project opens
Click edit
Click paste
This is a window of the plug-in
Search cloud
This is Claude's plugin, it needs to be restarted now, we will not restart it for the time being, and we need to search for another Substance plugin.
We still need to hook it up.
After the hookup is completed, close the window.
Let's go set up some other options.
We still need to find the editor, and find the project settings.
Let's search for Rui.
Then let's drag it to the bottom.
Select X11 here.
Then let's search for Translucent.
In this option, the part of the object is half-transparent.
Then hook it up.
After setting up these options,
we click restart immediately.
Restart takes some time.
After restarting, let's check these plugins.
We still find the editor.
Click on the plugin to find the installation.
We can see that our Claude plugin and Substance plugin have been installed.
Now open Claude.
Then open a project file.
This project file needs to be ensured.
We need to ensure the simulation function in Claude is turned off.
And we need Claude to be in the simulation mode or UV editing mode.
Ensure that Claude does not have an animation that is being recorded.
It is recommended to change the name of the object to the name of the text.
This will speed up the import.
I have already recorded an animation in advance.
Now let's play and check it out.
This is an animation that walks around the place.
If we press this button, the animation will stop and show the displayed select file.
Now point it.
Now we need to switch to casual mode.
That is normally the time.
Enable the basic condition of default mode.
That is active mode.
Let's refresh theWelcome window
Just wait for the video to be loaded.
You can know the music going on
when you open the key i button.
Save is the save button.
Click this button.
The saved resources will be saved according to the saved settings of the clothing, model, scene, and props, and stored in the specified folder in the content browser.
This button, S-Close, can be saved as KS-Close resources.
Live Sync Connection Status can be saved according to the connection status with CLO.
It will display green or red dots.
Now it is in the green dot display state.
This means that it can now successfully import these files opened in CLO.
If it shows red dots, then we need to check whether its version is correct.
The Live Sync version that you downloaded,
and the UE version,
and the CLO version,
are they corresponding to each other?
If it is still red after checking,
then you can do some simple operations in CLO.
For example, we can click on the paper,
or adjust the clothing.
If it still doesn't work,
you can restart CLO,
and then look at the options below.
This is the grid.
This is the texture.
Next, let's take a look at the garment.
This option includes clothing.
If you choose this option,
then you can import the clothing in CLO into the UE.
These two options below,
one is a single object,
and the other is a multiple object.
If we choose a single object,
then our clothing is a complete grid.
It is an integrated grid.
If we choose multiple objects,
then each of its panels,
each component,
is independent.
Now,
I choose a single object.
These two options below,
are both thin and thick.
Then it corresponds to
the display mode of the CLO texture surface.
The thin one represents the texture surface,
and the thick one represents the thick texture surface display.
This option below,
is a unified UV coordinate.
If we choose this option,
then we will use a unified UV coordinate option.
Then if we use this option,
we need to preview the clothing in CLO.
Include Garment Simulation Data.
It means that it contains clothing simulation data.
In fact,
it is the same as the option in the CLO
.
Using this option,
we save the clothing as the top number of
the top number of the Kiosk Cloth resources.
This function
is able to manually read the material in the UV.
This option,
Include Cache Animation,
contains the animation animation in the CLO.
If there is animation in CLO,
then we can make the choice.
It can bring the animation's clothing data into the UV,
then we can save it as a combined animation animation.
If the clothing and models
and we want to import it, we can click on this image.
Our costume and model can be played in this UE.
Then, let's look at the options after Avatar.
What about this one?
That is to say, it includes Avatar and virtual model.
If we click on this option, we can import the virtual model in CLO into UE.
Since the models of CLO have bone joints, they will be saved as a bone network.
This option is Avatar Animation.
After clicking on this option, the animation of this model will also be imported.
If we click on this item, it will display joint animation and save animation.
Then, the bottom is the scene and props.
If we click on this item,
when CLO contains this animation,
it will display the 3D resources of the scene and props.
Then, we can import the scene and props into UE.
Override Transparent Blend Mode is a transparent blend mode.
The two options at the bottom are semi-transparent and non-transparent.
This can be created by LiveSync.
For the costume material, choose a material blend mode.
Next, choose the desired option according to our needs.
For this option,
I will choose a single grid.
Then, choose the second one.
Since our project file contains animation,
I will choose animation.
Then, our model also contains animation.
So, I choose the model animation.
Then, choose joint animation.
After choosing,
we click on Update.
You can see that there will be a window like this,
which is what I just explained to you.
Some things to pay attention to.
The first is to ensure the simulation function in CLO.
Ensure that CLO is in the simulation mode or UV editor mode.
Ensure that CLO does not have the animation that is being recorded.
Then, click OK.
Now, our model and costume
are all imported to the UE window.
Click on the window that appears.
You can check it.
Our model and costume
can be seen in the big screen.
You can see the imported project file.
It is a USB format file.
Then, it will be divided into model files.
Naomi is our model file.
Then, there are also costume files.
It will be divided into these two files.
Click on the triangle to fold it up.
Next, click Save.
Save our model and costume files.
Before saving,
you can first
create a new folder about CLO.
Click on the new folder.
Then, click Save.
Find the created folder.
Click OK.
You need to wait for a while.
After saving,
the UE window will become blank.
Next, let's see
how to import and use the saved costume model into UE.
Go back to the selection mode.
In the content planning menu,
find the just saved folder.
This is our costume file.
The name of the file is the same as the project file.
It contains the garment costume file.
It is an integrated storage
and materials.
There is also an animation sequence about the model.
And the model's physical assets.
These are the parts for the costume.
Google's web font and other files.
There are also patterns.
This is a pattern of the model.
Next, I will explain to you
how to store the good costume and model files.
It will be used in the UE.
Open the first file clip.
Drag it to the UE window.
Then we open the third folder
Drag the first animation sequence in
In the position here, click to reset the value to default
Then click to reset the value to default
Now the costume is worn on the model
Click on the activated frame editor to run this frame in the mouth
Move the view, you can see
We recorded a good animation
Played in the UE window
Press Esc to exit
Open again
This is a scene file built in advance
Open the content planning menu
Put the model and costume in the scene file
Select the costume file in the scale
In the change
Position and rotation, click the back button to reset the value to default
Select the model file to perform the same operation
At the same time, select the model and costume files
Drag the moving axis to move the file to the desired position
Adjust the number of files to the right size
Use the rotation tool to rotate the file to the right position
Click on the
Click to run the structure to see the effect
Select the camera
In the view, select the stage animation mouth
Click to run the structure
Very good
Press F11 to fully ferment the current mouth
And switch to quiet mouth mode
You can move the mouse to view the entire scene
Finally, you can choose an ideal view
Click the left upper corner button
Choose high resolution screenshot
Enter the size of the screenshot you want
Click on Recover
Quickly output the current effect image
Finally, you can take a look at the performance of Claude's clothing in the UE scene
Thanks for watching and see you in the next video